# Adedamola Adesina Adeagbo

in Adedamola A. Adeagbo 🔗 Portfolio

#### **PROFILE**

Experienced Data Analyst and Brand Strategist with 3 years of experience. Increased marketing ROI by 20% and brand awareness by 200% in 1 year. Developed automated report system, improving efficiency by 20% in 2 years. Enhanced strategy effectiveness by 25% in 14 months.

#### **SKILLS**

- Tableau & Power BI Visualization
- Data Analysis & Interpretation
- Cross-functional Collaboration
- SQL (MSSQL, MySQL)
- Technical Presentation
- Critical Thinking
   & Problem Solving
- Data Modelling
- Statistical Knowledge
- Domain Knowledge
- Microsoft Suite (Word, Excel, Powerpoint & Outlook)
- Dashboard Design & Development

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

April 2022 – present

## **Business Intelligence Analyst (Marketing)**

49thStreet Media

- Increased sales team efficiency by 20% through the development of an automated report generation system, streamlining sales reporting processes.
- Enhanced data accessibility and decision-making efficiency by 15% with intuitive Tableau & Power BI dashboards, leading to improved data-driven decision-making processes.
- Contributed to a 20% increase in marketing ROI by conducting extensive primary and secondary research on digital marketing strategies, ads marketing, and brand promotions, leading to improved marketing effectiveness.
- Prepared detailed reports and presentations for stakeholders, contributing to strategic decision-making.
- Conducted data audits, validation and cleaning to maintain a high data accuracy and integrity.

March 2023 – February 2024

#### Data Analyst (Sales & Marketing)

Insurance Supermarket Inc

- Collaborated with marketing and sales teams for a targeted ad campaign, translating their business goals into specific data requirements. Analysed customer demographics and purchasing trends, which shaped the campaign strategy and resulted in a 20% increase in lead generation.
- Enhanced Sales team's forecasting accuracy by 6% through advanced analytical techniques.
- Implemented a new data quality checking process that improved data accuracy by 10%, reducing errors in reporting and improving the quality of insights provided to stakeholders.

- Developed and maintained Tableau dashboards to display key business metrics, improving the efficiency of decision-making processes by 30%.
- Conducted training sessions for team members on the use of Tableau, improving team productivity and data visualization skills.

## January 2022 – February 2023

## Brand Strategist & Social Media Analyst

#### Draft.co

- Achieved a 15% increase in content across social media platforms, resulting in expected growth and improved brand visibility.
- Identified and capitalized on 15% more opportunities through ongoing competitor analysis, leading to enhanced market position and strategic advantage.
- Enhanced strategy effectiveness by 25% through data-driven adjustments, utilizing Twitter and Instagram analytics tools, resulting in improved brand performance and engagement.
- Successfully generated a 200% increase in brand awareness over the span of one year.
- In-charge of creating dashboards and concise reports to effectively convey research findings to clients and internal stakeholders.

#### May 2021 - July 2022

#### **Automotive Service Advisor & Engineer**

Elizade-Toyota Nigeria Limited

- Monitoring a team of 5 auto technicians daily to ensure proper synergy between the customers and the technicians.
- Creating branding designs, employing online ads strategy and new a marketing approach which led to a 10% increase in sales of Toyota cars.
- In-charge of managing service routines of 15 cars and ensuring delivery at the expected time leading to a 15% reduction of service time.
- Handled a variety of administrative duties including scheduling of service appointments, cataloguing & handling customer's complaints and concerns, invoicing of receipts, and recording all service details for various customers.

## **PROJECTS**

#### May 2024

# Data Cleaning and Exploratory Analysis of a Global Electronics Retailer $\square$

- Using MySQL to implement and Extract, Transform and Load (ETL) Process to
  pull data from the different platforms and consolidate it into a single
  database.
- Performed data cleaning using **MySQL** to improve data quality and exploratory analysis to generate data-driven insights.
- Created a dashboard on **Power BI** for data visualization and validation of generated results from SQL queries to present to stakeholders.

#### April 2024

## Sales & Marketing Data for Pharmaceutical Company

Virtual Client's Project

- Utilized MySQL to extract data from 6 different related tables from customer sales databases using JOIN and VIEW.
- Transformed and filtered data by using aggregating and filtering function to improve reporting process.
- Performed data cleaning and data manipulation using power query on Excel to ensure data validity.
- Created a dashboard on Tableau for data visualization and to present actionable insights from the data.

March 2024

## Customer Churn Rate Analysis 🗷

Personal Project

- Transformed and processed client's data by using Power Query and Excel to ensure data completeness and validity.
- Created a dashboard with Tableau to help client compare between the churn rate, customer retention rate and customers who joined.
- Provided technical insights on how the client can fully utilize their data to determine where stronger marketing actions are required.
- Consulted with client to determine the best metrics to be displayed on final product.

January 2024

## Market Analysis & Insights on US Coffee Market

Personal Project

- Transformed and filtered data by using aggregating and filtering function to improve reporting process
- Established a foundation for a data-driven decision-making approach, leading to more effective strategies and stronger business outcomes.
- Created interactive dashboards in Tableau to visually represent the data and make the findings more comprehensible.

#### **EDUCATION**

March 2014 – June 2019

#### **B.Sc. Mechanical Engineering**

Obafemi Awolowo University, Ile-Ife, Osun, Nigeria.

#### **CERTIFICATES**

- Microsoft Power BI Developer (2024)
- Tableau Certified Developer (2023)
- Certified Data Analyst IBM (2022)
- SEO Fundamentals Google (2022)

## **FURTHER EDUCATION (COURSES)**

May 2024 SQL for Data Science ☑

University of California

November 2023 Python for Data Science, AI & Development

**IBM** 

June 2021 Marketing Analytics 🛮

University of Virginia

October 2020 Brand Management: Aligning Business, Brand and Behaviour

University of London

May 2020 Google SEO Fundamentals ♂

University of California, Davis

April 2020 Project Manager

**International Project Management Association**